Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]





Senior Consultant seeking roles in Software Application, Full stack web applications development, Software Development, Software Design, Configuration Management, Ansible, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Python, C#, VB, Javascript, Shell Scripting



Current Designation: Senior System Engineer

Current Company: EPAM Systems

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Consultant, Software Developer, Software Application, Full stack web applications development, Software Development, Software Design, Configuration Management, Ansible, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Python, C#, VB,

Javascript, Shell Scripting

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

8+ years of Professional experience in Full stack web applications development, currently working as DevOps Engineer and Cloud practitioner

Skilled in AWS Cloud stack, Terraform, Ansible, Codefresh, JFrog, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm

Actively involved in Agile, Kanban projects, SDLC environments with various Design, Coding and Testing frameworks Worked in various functional domains such as Customer & Marketing, Retails, Insurance & Health care.

Strong analytical, problem solving, relationship building, organizational, planning, team building, mentoring, negotiation, and communication skills.

Work Experience

EPAM Systems as Senior System Engineer

Dec 2020 to Till Date

Working as Cloud & DevOps Engineer for a client in Financial sector

Deloitte as Senior Consultant

May 2017 to Dec 2020

Selected Project Highlights

Industry/Client and Location: Commerce and Digital Marketing. Duration: 18 months

Project Description/Scope: Build CI/CD pipelines for various projects developed under our Product Eco-System. This

involved Python, .Net, NodeJs, Vue applications and Some ETL tools such as Talend.

Role: Senior Technical Consultant

Responsibilities/Deliverables:

- Engage with projects tech leads to understand technical components and strategize delivery pipelines
- Analyze requirements and build Docker images and manage artifactory
- Build Helm charts and test deployments on kubernetes clusters
- Prepare a complete CI/CD pipeline using Codefresh for dev teams to ease the deployments.

Achievements: In this short term period, I got familiar with various tools and have trained 3 junior practitioners to help them get on boarded to our team.

Duration: 12 months

Industry/Client and Location: Commerce & Digital Marketing. Project Description/Scope: Modernization of Product Suite

Role: Technical Consultant

Responsibilities/Deliverables:

- * To build Cloud agnostic micro services of existing assets which were based on .net 2.0 Framework
- * Made enhancements to increase application performance and scalability, built various DB connectors (Mongodb, PostgreSql. Redis) so that applications can fit into client eco-systems
- * Built Docker containers (Linux and Windows based) to increase portability of applications and created automated Codefresh pipelines for code deployments to Kubernetes systems
- * Also involved in client deployments and managing customizations based on client requirements.

Achievements: Effectively applied best practices and modernized various .net applications to High performing, scalable micro services.

Industry/Client and Location: Health Care Duration: 8 months

Project Description/Scope: Build a centralized, omni-channel application that provides end user a detailed, real-time view of Lab Experiments that have been carried out at a Lab Research Center

Role: Technical Consultant

Responsibilities/Deliverables:

- * Build backend micro services that are deployed to AWS Lambdas
- * Engaging with UI team to understand the data requirements that can be sourced from backend API's
- * Understand complex client subsystems to analyze the data sources and manipulations as per application requirements
- * Build connectors to manage Integrations to various client components such as WCS, Saleforce, Hana etc
- * Worked on CICD pipelines and automated deployments through Jenkins to deploy .net Core microservices to AWS environments

Achievements: Involved in UAT, Staging and Prod deployments with Client Technical team and helped improve the application performance and manage Cloudwatch, Alerting mechanisms

Other Project Initiatives with Deloitte

- * Built various tools and POC's outside project to help Organization with certain Internal Initiatives and Client challenges
- * Participated in 2 day Adobe-Microsoft hack-a-thon to build a Chatbot application with Azure Tech Stack.
- * Developed A web based chat bot application that connects with in-house marketing web-site which performs all the e-commerce activities such as login, Search Products, Product Recommendations, View Cart, Wishlist items, Check-out items and etc. making website activities simpler.
- * Built a Facial-recognition enable Digital signage software that does Ad-ranking based on sentiment analysis, which helps service providers to enhance the ad-campaigns

Infosys as Senior System Engineer Apr 2015 to May 2017

Hansa Solutions India pvt Itd as Software Developer Sep 2012 to Apr 2015

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Ansible, Terraform, Docker	
Kubernetes, Helm, Jfrog, Codefresh	
Amazon Web Services, Azure	
SQL, PostgreSql, MongoDB, Redis	
Python, C#, VB, JavaScript	
SQL, Shell Scripting	
.Net Core, .Net Framework	

1/22/2021 $https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=6c6ffe2346cd5ad71b3d369a1efb23f30a54015143105d1505164950090\dots$

WCF, Microservices Architecture	
Linux, Windows	
Chatbots, Cognitive services, NLP servic	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english				
hindi				
telugu				
marathi				
Kannada				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization